Guide to the Judith Osgood Papers, 1950-1988
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Judith Osgood Papers,
1950-1988
Osgood, Judith
2 boxes
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, diaries, photographs, manuscript writings, and ephemera documenting the life and career of Judith Osgood.
Biographical Note
Judith Osgood graduated from Vassar College in 1955 and went on to a successful career in journalism. One of a number of pioneering women journalists during the 1960s, in 1966, while working for CBS News, she persuaded her superiors to send her to Vietnam, where she covered the war for CBS News radio until August 1967. While a reporter for CBS, Osgood became close to such notable figures as CBS executive Richard Salant and journalist Morley Safer.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of correspondence, diaries, photographs, manuscript writings, and ephemera documenting the life and career of Judith Osgood. The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence between Osgood and CBS News colleagues, regarding news coverage of the Vietnam War. Correspondence reveals the logistical challenges of war reporting during the 1960s and the camaraderie of key CBS news bureau stakeholders covering the Vietnam War.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Herford, Peter; Reasoner, Harry, 1923-1991; Safer, Morley; Salant, Richard S., 1914-1993
Organizations:
CBS News; Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae
Subjects:
Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Journalists; Women journalists--United States--20th century
Encoding Information
Encoded by Janine St. Germain, August-September 2020
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Johnson Rare Books and Archives (M2020-001).
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence
- Series II. Journals
- Series III. Biographical Materials
- Series IV. Writings
- Series V. Photographic Prints
Container List
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Correspondence from Judith Osgood
    - Osgood, Mrs. Cornelius (mother), 1952 (Folder 1.1)
    - Salant, Richard, 1966-1967 (Folder 1.2-1.4)
  - Correspondence to Judith Osgood
    - General, 1962 (Folder 1.5)
    - General, postcards, 1952-1978 (Folder 1.6)
    - Holiday cards, Japan Quarterly, NHK, 1960-1969 (Folder 1.7)
    - Salant Richard, 1966-1967 (Folder 1.8-1.9)
    - Herford, Peter, 1966 (Folder 1.10)
    - McWhirter, William, 1967 (Folder 1.11)
    - Osgood, Corneilius (father), 1973-1977 (Folder 1.12)
    - Pearce, John Ed, undated (Folder 1.13)
    - Reasoner, Harry, 1967; (includes carbon copy of Osgood letter) (Folder 1.14)
    - Safer, Morley, 1967 (Folder 1.15)
    - Sakamoto, Hiroshi, NHK, 1966 (Folder 1.16)
    - Salant, Richard to Manning, Paskman, 1966-1967 (Folder 1.17)
- SERIES II. JOURNALS
  - Weekly Reminder, 1950 (Folder 1.18)
  - Japan, summer trip, 1961 (Folder 1.19)
  - My Trip Abroad, 1952; (includes correspondence) (Folder 1.20)
  - Summer, 1954 (Folder 1.21)
  - Datebooks, 1962-1964; (includes correspondence) (Folder 1.22-1.23)
- SERIES III. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
  - IDs, press cards, ration card, 1967 (Folder 1.24)
  - Osgood Estate, property, Keenville, IL, 1977-1988 (Folder 1.25)
- SERIES IV. WRITINGS
  - Essaays, notes, 1952-1953; (typescripts, manuscripts) (Folder 2.1)
  - "My Values are Abstract and Idealistic...,", undated; (typescript) (Folder 2.2)
  - Scientific Attitude, Jack Street, undated; (typescript) (Folder 2.3)
- SERIES V. PHOTOGRAPHIC PRINTS
  - Osgood, Judith, portraits, snapshots, approximately 1950-1980 (Folder 2.4-2.5)
  - Osgood, Judith, with family, friends, colleagues, 1950-1969 (Folder 2.6)
  - Osgood, Judith, professional, 1960-1969 (Folder 2.7)
  - Friends, family, colleagues, 1960-1979 (Folder 2.8)
  - Locations, 1960-1970 (Folder 2.9)